Nabil Douss

Berlin, 13403 | +49 176 87823496

n.douss97@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/nabil-douss

Hey there! I'm a Senior Consultant in Indirect Tax Technology at EY with a tech background as a full-stack developer. I've spent 5 years building cool stuff with various technologies such as Next.JS, ASP .NET, and Python, while also unraveling the intricacies of business transactions through data analytics.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Consultant Oct 2023 - Present

EY Tax GmbH Steuerberatungsgesellschaft, Berlin

- Co-engineered a Next.JS web application for processing, querying, and visualizing business transactions, enhancing data accessibility.
- Co-developed and maintained a tax determination engine in C# and ASP.NET, improving data quality analysis, classification, and tax compliance for SAP business transactions.
- Integrated an Al-powered copilot chatbot into the UI using Azure OpenAl & Langchain, enabling:
 - o RAG-based Q&A for tax-related inquiries
 - Natural language to MongoDB aggregations for data interaction
 - Automated tax determination via .NET API
 - VAT-ID validation using third-party APIs
- Conceptualized and co-engineered Al-driven agents for extracting, mapping, and analyzing data from structured and unstructured sources:
 - OCR-based PDF parsing and data extraction
 - Automated mapping of CSV/TSV to custom data models
 - Unified data integration across multiple sources
 - o Advanced analytics: keyword search, VAT determination, compliance checks
- Mentored and managed a team of 3 junior consultants, fostering technical growth and team efficiency.

Consultant Oct 2022 - Oct 2023

Ernst & Young GmbH Wirtschaftsprüfungsgesellschaft, Berlin

- Optimized a backend server in JavaScript & GraphQL that processes real-time queries on transactions, while maintaining a MongoDB database.
- Co-developed a Vue.js web dashboard for monitoring, filtering and reviewing SAP business transactions.
- Migrated a desktop solution to a web application using ASP.NET, optimizing backend processes including data transfer, analysis, third-party API communication, and SQL Server maintenance.
- Enhanced quality assurance by implementing 80+ unit tests with XUnit, conducting code reviews, defect analysis, and corrections.

Working Student Jun 2019 - Oct 2022

EDUCATION

Master of Science (M.S.) - Data Science & Engineering Oct 2019 - Jun 2022

Technische Universität Berlin (Grade 1.2)

Master thesis: "Multi-domain Sentiment Analysis with an Active Learning Mechanism". The thesis proposes three model architectures for binary sentiment analysis on multi-domain textual data using an Active Learning mechanism.

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) - Computer Science

Oct 2016 - Jan 2020

Technische Universität Berlin (Grade 1.5)

• Bachelor thesis: "An Analysis of Lightweight Cryptographic Algorithms".

PUBLICATIONS

ACM SAC Conference (SAC'23)

2023

Katerina Katsarou, Nabil Douss, and Kostas Stefanidis. 2023. REFORMIST: Hierarchical Attention Networks for Multi-Domain Sentiment Classification with Active Learning. In Proceedings of ACM SAC Conference (SAC'23). ACM, New York, NY, USA, Article 4, 10 pages.

SKILLS

IT-Skills

- Programming languages: JavaScript / Python / C# / Java
- Frameworks: React / Next.JS / VueJS / ASP .NET
- Machine Learning: PyTorch / Keras / Tenserflow / Scipy / Pandas
- Database Systems: MySQL / SQL Server / MongoDB

Language Skills

- German, Professional proficiency
- French, Professional proficiency
- English, Professional proficiency
- Arabic, Native language